--http://7ays.com--
情书
The Love Letter
1998年贺曼频道出品
听译，意译，时间轴：terrence
学生一枚，水平有限，请见谅！
太漂亮了
- 进去看看？
- 好啊
你好，两位。我叫雅各布・坎贝尔
她是个大美人，对吧？
- 我能试试看吗？
- 噢，衣服不外卖
它是奶奶的遗物
只是为了吸引顾客，尤其是年轻的小姐们
那些有人陪伴的
呵呵，精明的做法
- 这里有更多
- 好的
- 你是个南北战争的爱好者？
- 是啊，可以这么说
- 介意我看看这些吗？
- 你看吧
我自己也藏有一些
- 前几天我刚弄到了这东西
- 历史可久了
- 真不错
- 太漂亮了
- 桌子是内战时一个将军的
是啊？
黛布拉你过来看看
- 很棒吧？
- 看起来老掉牙了
我正需要一张书桌
- 你给个价
- 我本来准备自己藏着的，但是...
如果你真的要，800刀吧
- 噢，太贵了
- 600刀怎么样？
这东西是十九世纪的耶，
800是我能给的最低的了
太贵了
第一次看你这么冲动
我需要更多的自发性
希望下次你再这样的话，
是一些...轻点的东西
你知道你有多可爱吗
绝对是个写东西的好地方
毫无疑问！
哪个时候得给它打打蜡，抛抛光
- 我该走了
- 你走吧
好吧
- 做个美梦
- 你也是
伊丽莎白・威仕肯
1863年4月16日
亲爱的，午夜已过
终于我可以自由地向你倾述了
母亲，父亲还有弗洛丝说了晚安
而我更想要一个安静美好的夜晚
我29岁了，得到了几个先生的约见
但只有你是我的唯一
即便你不是真实的，你也比今晚那个
拉着我的手向我求婚的男人珍贵
我根本不喜欢他
虽然我尝试过去恳求父亲
不幸的是，我必须服从
并且尽快接受
但是我为炽烈燃烧的爱火
还有皎洁的月光而痛苦着
我用灵魂和心灵和你交谈
如果你真的存在的话
晚安，亲爱的
梦中与我相会
亲爱的女士
我刚刚在你的书桌
一个神秘的隔层里发现你的信
我读了它们
希望我能给你一些帮助
我知道这是对你父亲的一份义务
但你还是应该遵循你的心声
和你不爱的人结婚是一个错误
不要绝望，那个梦中情人
也许现在就在你周围，任何地方
谁知道呢，或许我就是你要找的人
但是亲爱的，很不幸
我已把我的心献给了郝思嘉（乱世佳人女主）
永远是你的挚爱，白瑞特（乱世佳人男主）
你哪个时候能弄完？
不用担心，很快就好
这游戏会毁了我们的圣诞假期的
反正我会准备好的
那最好了，不然我们有麻烦的
不，不要中断（指游戏）
- 有信息
- 波斯顿
我看看，
哦，在这里
- 威洛比的一个地方
- 在哪里？
北面大概半小时路程，塞勒姆旁边
地址是，米尔普莱恩路3号
那是郊区的一座老房子
6分52秒，还不够快啊，目标是6分50
我已经很高兴了，你们呢？
我累得不行啦
来吧再来，我们只有6星期了
教练说呢，再来一次吧
这是私人财产，你已经侵犯了
- 抱歉，我不是有意的，我只是…
- 快给我滚！
我只是好奇以前有人住在这儿
到底你对这有什么好好奇的
我们可没有兴趣，
克莱思小姐出去了，没人在家
但是，女士...
第二课
（意大利语）
- 谢谢（意大利语的谢谢）
- 谢谢
准备得怎么样了，妈妈
- 出行前应该了解一下当地的文化嘛
- 你做到了，妈妈
不要再叫我碧奇思了，
我要人人都叫我碧奇基（意大利名字）
你儿子还是可以这么叫你吧？
你把该花在婚礼上的花了
然后你和黛布拉就可以去环球旅行了
- 我可不要
- 那是你的问题
你整天住在你那小世界里，多郁闷啊
是吗？
实际上我刚刚回了一封134年的情书
- 是吗？
- 嗯，我在一张老旧的书桌里找到那些信
我梦着你
用心灵与灵魂和你交谈，只希望你真的存在
- 你都记着？
- 嗯，好伤感
所以，我就...回了信
那你寄了吗？
我寄了，但邮局不相信我
所以我寄了特快专递
别自作聪明了！
威尔斯（英国小说家）相信时光旅行
爱因斯坦认为时间只是另一个维度
而一些人认为灵魂能穿越时空
你穿越去意大利了
你有地址吗？
我如果告诉了你，你又会借题发挥了
看我的邮箱？
你的邮件？
日期是1863年，寄过来要一点时间哦
- 你在哪里拿到的？
- 在书桌里，一个秘密的隔间
- 开玩笑吧，哪里？
- 我才刚进来
问问而已
这里面有个小按钮可以打开它
哇
真可怜
幻想主义者一个
却和失败者或父母内定的人结婚
也许她没有和他结婚
那可是19世纪60年代
她当然只能那样做
我去弄晚餐
1863年从波斯顿到威洛比的邮件只需1分钱
小心，在那时可不便宜
一瓶墨水，威迪文（最古老的制笔公司）
当时款式的复制品
等等
我们要什么东西都尽善尽美！
妈妈，停下
假设我真的是彻底疯了
那我应该在哪里把回信寄出去？
城里北部的曼哈塞帝邮局
建于1857年，
是南北战争前的邮局中唯一还在的
24小时都可以寄存信件
晚上去吧，我不知道为什么
但是看起来更合适
等等
这真的行得通吗？
如果可以的话，那岂不是很好吗？
即便你不是真实的，你也比今晚那个
拉着我的手向我求婚的男人珍贵
我根本不喜欢他
虽然我尝试过去恳求父亲
不幸的是，我必须服从
并且尽快接受
但是我为炽烈燃烧的爱火
还有皎洁的月光而痛苦着
我用灵魂和心灵和你交谈
如果你真的存在的话
晚安，亲爱的。在梦中与我相会
亲爱的女士
我刚刚读了你的信…
…梦中情人也许现在就在你的周围
任何地方
谁知道呢，或许我就是你要找的人
一个朋友
邮局好远啊，不过我来了
- 下午好，波特先生
- 你也是，玛姬
伊丽莎白！
弗洛丝，你见过你的姐姐吗？
她在花园里，爸爸
- 威仕肯小姐
- 里格先生
我正巧有点事经过，就来了
多好啊
- 漂亮的花，对吧？
- 是很漂亮
她在午夜盛开...
但到早晨，就随风消逝了
我试着给她写首诗
我衷心希望你写完诗后念给我听
我相信你的诗一定是...赏心悦目的
谢了
多么美好的黄昏
我只是在练习
不，我在想，威仕肯小姐，丽茜？
什么事，里格先生？
我只是想知道你是否充分考虑了
上次我们见面时我的建议？
噢，我仍在考虑着
很高兴听你这么说
我想我头有些痛，先去休息了
爸爸，妈妈，弗洛丝，晚安
丽茜，我忘了
这是你的一封信
谢谢妈妈
会好的，亲爱的
- 丽茜？
- 爸爸？
母亲和我纳闷着你可能有什么要说的
没有啊
我之前和里格聊了会
他要我相信你们两个正在培养默契
我只是把您所谓的培养默契理解成开始而已
那么这个开始
会最终成为默契吗？
然后是订婚？
和婚姻？
爸爸，我不爱他
你已经29了，丽茜
爸爸，我知道你们总是为我着想
而我也知道，什么是我所期望的
这可不是我们要的期望
常识是，在你这个年纪的女人，
无论什么情况
都无法承受被拒绝的命运...
丽茜？
- 头痛？
- 是的，爸爸
- 有什么需要我做的吗？
- 没，我只需要休息
你是谁？
你到底是谁？
先生，今天我收到你的信
你的胆识令我吃惊
你到底是谁？你又是怎么知道
我这个秘密的隔间的？
当我放下另一份信时，我疑惑
我是陷在疯狂的梦境里
还是将再次受到你的侵犯
震惊的，伊丽莎白・威仕肯
亲爱的伊丽莎白
我肯定你也会和我一样吃惊的
我叫斯科特・柯里根，我住在波斯顿
但不是你知道的那个波斯顿
当我在我的桌子，
应该是你的桌子，读到这些字句时
我现在拥有这张桌子
读到你的回信时，我想也太荒唐了
而我唯一能给的解释是
出于某些原因，我们的联系是如此强烈
令我们能通过时空交流
如果你还觉得我在吓唬你
不要害怕，尽快回我信
你真诚的，斯科特・柯里根
丽茜？
- 天哪，怎么回事？
- 没
你吓坏了我，我...我刚刚走神了
- 那是因为信里的东西吗？
- 什么信？
你不想让我看到的信
噢，它啊
不，只是我又被一家出版社拒绝了
噢，丽茜，很抱歉
你的诗是。。。非凡的！
那也要人家的杂志也这么认为时才是
我还是不明白为什么
你不给里格先生的杂志社投稿？
我已经投过了，在等回音呢
肯定会有人发表你的诗的
你要耐心
亲爱的柯里根先生
我决定接受是某种自然定律
在我们身上起作用了
暂时莫名其妙地生效了
Ok，那很简单
- 但是，餐具呢？
- 餐具，是啊
你有比我好的条件，知道了我最秘密的秘密
而我没有
告诉我，你是谁，还有
在这么多年后的未来你是怎么生活的
- 这根怎么样？
- 那长得…太科幻了
最重要的是
告诉我你我之间的强烈感应
这种心灵上的联系
是否也让你感受到深刻而热烈的爱情？
这个怎么样？
或者你已经有爱的人了
尽快回信，趁现在自然定律仍有效时
- 也许我们得让别人给我们选？
- 不要，抱歉
亲爱的丽茜，你问了我些很关键的问题
我有吗？
我有放入肉豆蔻吗？
肉豆蔻？放在你的蛋糕里？
你的口味也太奇怪了！
肉桂，我是说我加了肉桂进去
我渴望爱吗？当然了
我正在热恋中吗？
我已经订了婚，我相信我是在热恋中的
相信...
相信什么，小姐？
我相信这会是一个美味的蛋糕，你不认为吗？
是的，小姐。我去帮妈妈手，再见
朋友说，当你热恋时，看到恋人走近你
你会满心欢喜，
就像一棵开满彩灯的圣诞树
而我不觉得有过那种感觉
直到昨晚，当我收到你第二封信时
- 你寄了几封信了？
- 3封
你肯定没有人…
在捣乱？不可能！
不，这才是不可能的！
那你为什么一开始还支持我？
但是我怎么都想不到...
- 黛布拉怎么看的？
- 我没有告诉她
你没有告诉她？
- 不可置信对不？
- 我告诉你什么才是不可置信吧
我这个快结婚的儿子竟然
爱上一个死了100多年的女子！
妈，我们写过信
你们在写情书，还偷偷背着你的未婚妻
伊丽莎白・威仕肯又怎样？
再说你没有资格去干预人家的生活
她不爱那个男的，她不该和他结婚
我们该走了，罗马在等着你呢
真不敢相信我们都说了些什么
- 这女的根本不存在！
- 那么谁写了这些信？
反正在你我生存的世界，她不存在
那为什么我感觉到了...我感觉到的？
那又是什么？
我亲爱的丽茜
我忍不住想告诉你，
当我读到你的信时有多么激动
我只希望能把你搂入怀中...
- 波特先生，你再查查看好吗？
- 好的，丽茜小姐
抱歉了，没有你的信
亲爱的，又一周过去了，还是没有回音
你是怕我至从告诉我你订婚后
我会认为你对我动情是可耻的吗？
我是怕我对你的感情一发不可收拾
我可没有你想的那样天真，柯里根先生
我可是和很多男士共舞过
并且读过很多现代小说了
所以我知道哪些东西是不该有的
恐怕舞只能由我和黛布拉跳了，威仕肯女士
残酷的事实是，你我都注定是别人的了
我们从未碰过，
听过对方讲话或看过对方一面
而只是互通信件又有什么害处呢？
如果你还在那里，快回我信
告诉我像圣诞树一样
焕发光芒到底是什么一回事
- 早上好
- 又是你
真的很抱歉，
我只是想知道一些威仕肯家族的事情
为什么？
我买了一张桌子，那曾经是他们家族的
然后我就对这个家族感兴趣了
我还写了一本有关他们的书
一本书？他们只是普通人
那你知道他们吗？
克莱思的奶奶是威仕肯女士
- 克莱思？
- 我照顾的女士
你是说现在还有威仕肯家族的人住这？
是啊
我照顾她多年了，可知道她的古怪脾气
我很想和她聊会，行吗？
她睡了
我知道这很冒犯
但你介意我只看一眼吗？只是一眼
我为什么要允许呢？
我给这房子上墙漆吧
就这一面
如果你是克莱思那贱表弟的某个贱律师
那我可放不过你，进来吧
谢了
- Ok，先生，你已经看过一眼了
- 再看会
谁啊？
看你做的好事！
克莱思
你是谁
这家伙写了本有关威仕肯家族的书
他想见见你
你好，夫人。我叫斯科特
- 别傻了，他就是律师
- 不，我不是律师
我已经说过，我不会离开这房子
直到一个好的律师把我带走
我只是想找一些有关伊丽莎白・威仕肯的资料
别骗我了，滚开
我警告过你
你怎么会知道丽茜？
我找到她的信，
在一张曾经放在这里的旧桌子里
弗洛丝告诉我很多我姨奶奶的故事
她真的很美
但是我从没见过她
你能告诉我她结婚了吗？
我要睡了
我想知道她是否结过婚，女士？
过来吧
好的
亲爱的丽茜：
富兰克林发现了电
我们现在用它来发动电器
点来我们的房子还有，圣诞树
早上好，丽茜小姐
谢谢
点亮圣诞树
意味洋溢着快乐，而现在我已是充满快乐了
我去了你在米尔普莱恩路的房子，它还在
一个很老的女士――你妹妹的孙女住在里面
而我确实就在你的房间呆过
但我真正不能忘怀的，
是我突然在楼梯上感觉到了你的存在
就像...你几乎就碰到了我的胸口
这很诧异但，感觉像我也触到了你
丽茜，无视这一切将是对奇迹的排斥
原谅我之前的沉默，我承诺不会再发生了
深爱你的，斯科特
亲爱的斯科特，我恳求你守住承诺
永远不要停笔，感觉我快要停止呼吸了
我的气息都为你在我房里流连的影子而停止
就在这个房子里，
令人惊喜的是，也是在楼梯上
我也有相似的感觉
是你甜蜜诺言般的触摸
我知道我们要面对着命运
还有把你我世界分开的残酷现实
但我们穿过了时空，分享了爱和生活
我也有同感
我梦里都是你，但是我不知道你的样子
请寄给我你的照片
记住，你不能动
我只想看到你，无限接近我的双臂
- 喂
- 嗨，怎么样？
- 很好
- 你呢？好极了
你好高兴，怎么啦？
因为你在这里啊
噢，真会讨好人
那是什么？
额，伊丽莎白・威仕肯
- 信里的那个？
- 是啊
- 你在哪里弄的？
- 她住过的老房子里
- 你去过她的房子？
- 是啊
- 为什么？
- 好奇而已
你到底是怎么找到的？
我碰到了一个古玩店的老板，
他正从威洛比的健身房走出来
我想我应该感到庆幸
因为我的情敌已经死了
这些地是准备卖出去的
我知道你热爱自然
所以最近我都忙于在这一带找合适的地方
来建未来我们…一起住的房子
十分感谢
我很好奇你是否看过一个月前我给你的诗稿
是啊，我读过
- 那么？
- 很有趣
富有激情
但在技巧上，还不太成熟
拿那些断开的字词，句子来说
你有独到的看法，但你需要一个导师
我希望在将来，我能在你每个方面...
都给些指导
我决定不再写诗了
我想里格“大人”那套
太陈旧，不能很好接受我的作品
除非...它们被其他人所重视
但我亲爱的，事实是
不会有人重视的了
我吟唱着，但是除了你，我没有知音
所以我给你我最后的一首诗
- 你和黛布拉快结婚了？
- 是的
很快了
- 你的书很不错
- 谢了
我。。。我能求你个忙吗？
介意看看一首诗，说说你的感受吗？
你想让我点评你的诗作？
不是我的，是朋友的短诗，介意吗？
- 行
- 谢谢
陌生的你，我们不该相会
但我又渴望和你在一起...
告诉他不要放弃
这诗有什么问题吗？
这是什么？老套的...又过于感性的？
我打算帮忙发表这些诗，你怎么看？
- 你还好吧？
- 至少在你说这句话之前
- 好吧，有什么不对劲吗？
- 你有问题
- 我有？
- 对
- 怎么回事？
我玷污了他朋友那首圣洁的诗
你们在说什么诗？哪个朋友？
没什么
都吵成这样了，还没有？
嗯...是伊丽莎白・威仕肯，
我又找到她的信
只是觉得有些历史价值
那确实
黛布拉！
- 你怎么了？
- 没什么
首先，你不跟我说找到她那些信
然后你悄悄去她的房子，你也没说
还有她的照片，她的诗呢！
亲爱的，不要夸大
不！你把更多的精力放在这个女的上面，
而不是我们的婚礼
- 不是那样的
- 为什么？
- 你是害怕结婚还是...？
- 我不理解
如果你真不想结，就吱一声吧
你要老实告诉我，不然我就取消婚礼
亲爱的，不要，没什么比婚礼重要了
我真的很抱歉，亲爱的
我错了，都是我的错
亲爱的丽茜：
不要停止写你的诗
这个叫里格的家伙似乎连什么是诗都不知道
你说你没有知音
也许暂时没有，但十年后呢，百年后呢？
你说我们注定不能触摸到对方
但你用你的诗，真切地触动了我
继续吟唱你的诗吧，我的挚爱
我会一直用心聆听的
弗洛丝，没啥可以担心的
那为什么你要老远去波斯顿？
医生觉得我的头痛可能和眼睛有关
还介绍了波斯顿一位专家
我和你一起去，
反正堂姐有足够的地方让我们住
不要，弗洛丝
我要你在这里帮我
告诉你一些听起来不可思议的东西
可能有些病态，但绝对真实
你要承诺不干涉我，直到我回来
各就各位，预备...开始！
那么我要把你寄给我的
写给柯里根先生的信
放在那个隔间，关上，它们就...
还要保证把他的信秘密寄到堂姐那儿
他没事吧？
心电图显示他的心律有些失常
但幸运的是，整体状况还是稳定的
他哪个时候能醒过来？
目前还难说
我是伊丽莎白・威仕肯，找里德医生
- 坐坐吧，威仕肯小姐
- 谢谢
下一个就是你了，威仕肯小姐
邓比上校
- 周五再过来
- 好的，医生
威仕肯小姐，进来吧
我很抱歉
- 是你，威仕肯小姐
- 邓比上校
- 真是巧啊！
- 请见谅
没关系，你看起来像有急事
是的
好吧，我不打扰了
我能陪你走走吗？
我不想弄乱你的计划
不，没有，我没有什么事...
你去哪里？
事实上...我也不知道
我请你喝杯怎么样，然后再决定去哪里
好啊
你是里德医生的长期病人？
不，我第一次来
你...现在感觉还好吧？
嗯，很不错
我能问你一个古怪的问题吗？
问吧
我有十足把握我们见过面
不知道为什么，但我也有同感
亲爱的斯科特，这天下午
我遇到一个叫凯勒・邓比的绅士
他是马塞诸塞州19号部队的上校
在见到他的一刻，我就被深深吸引了
而他看起来对我也有好感
亲爱的不必担心我就这样离你远去
因为和凯勒・邓比在一起，某种感觉
让我觉得和你贴得更近了
我奇怪于这一切似乎都是注定发生的
- 你说过要念给我听的
- 噢不
好吧
不许笑啊
陌生的你，我们不该相会
但我又渴望和你在一起...
我会一直等待你...
他没事，会没事的
亲爱的斯科特，我怕再也联系不上你了
弗洛丝确定说我给你的信
仍是一封封消失在隔间的
所以但愿你我还是联系着
还是用信件点亮彼此的心灵
各位女士和先生，感谢莅临
请允许我来介绍发表讲话的客人
他将告诉你们各位的到场和慷慨捐赠
对那些为国负伤的士兵来讲是多么有意义
这位勇敢的军官在昌塞洛斯维尔战役中受伤
但他这个星期就会重回他的军队
热烈欢迎来自马塞诸塞州19号部队的
凯勒・邓比上校！
你没有告诉我今晚你会来
我想给你个惊喜
- 你很快就要回军队？
- 恐怕是的
- 我们还有多少时间？
- 我后天走
丽茜，我想单独见你，今晚亭子见，好吗？
可我的堂姐在那儿...
她昏昏欲睡呢
丽茜
- 他们设定了日程
- 谢谢
也许你需要休息一下？
不，我不累，没事
只是还在恢复
- 你还好吧？！
- 我没事
- 我取消掉聚会吧
- 不我可以的，黛布拉
只是有点晕，医生说很正常的
妈妈回来了，你去陪陪她吧
- 我会很快好起来的
- 好吧
- 一定要给我电话
- 我会的
斯科特
当你在医院醒过来时...
怎么了？
没事，很高兴你出院了
我也是
我强烈地被他吸引了
而他也对我很有好感
很快他就要回到军队里了
他说一场关键的战争
在宾夕法尼亚州南部某个地方爆发了
亲爱的，我很害怕
宾夕法尼亚州南部某个地方？
1863年在宾夕法尼亚州南部
宾夕法尼亚州南部...
葛底斯堡！
（美国南北战争）
葛底斯堡...葛底斯堡...
（死伤人口）
马塞诸塞州19号...
（以团为单位）
百分之五十
凯勒・邓比上校，7月3号死于战争
1863年6月28号
亲爱的丽茜
不要让邓比上校回到他的军队
- 你去哪里？
- 邮局
- 你才刚出院！
- 我得给伊丽莎白寄封信
你还不能开车，我来开吧
- 前面什么建筑着火了？
- 那是邮局！
- 不要靠近火场
- 不，我得进去！
不行！请退到栅栏外！
不要过去！
留在这里，我一会就来，留着！
不，斯科特，快回来！
我回来后你会嫁给我吗？
当然会的
- 你肯定吗，弗洛丝？
- 我每天都看着
那我给他的信呢？
它们在隔间里消失了，和你说的一样
他承诺过回我信的
亲爱的丽茜
里格先生过来了
噢不，妈妈，现在我不能看他
你父亲说了你会下楼的
就随便弄弄妆容吧
我肯定看到他你会精神焕发的
我确实和格兰特将军的军队呆过
而西进运动将会...
- 这场战争会赢得迅速而彻底的
- 对的，先生
欢迎回来，威仕肯女士。我们都很想念你
谢谢，里格先生
请见谅，但我实在很劳累，旅途很长
所以我想晚些再聊吧
丽茜，里格先生会和我们吃晚餐
玛姬？
- 有我的信吗？
- 有的，就这封？
丽茜，你能考虑下客人的感受吗？
一会儿，爸爸
丽茜，写了什么？
去拿我的包包，快点！
爸爸，我得去一趟车站
你不刚从车站回来吗？信里写了什么！
里格先生，你能载我一程吗？
亲爱的，只要让你高兴就行
但我不能违背你父亲的意愿...
那我就走去
- 不准那样！
- 我不是小孩了
你拦不了我
就让她自个儿滚远去吧！
沃伦！你怎可以这样？
弗洛丝，她究竟和你说了什么？
丽茜！
不好意思
有去葛底斯堡的火车吗？
不行啊，能去的最近的就是哈里斯堡了
再往下去的线路被叛军切掉了
- 一路你得小心啊
- 谢谢！
- 喂！
- 嗨，你在这里？
是啊
看我拿了什么
他们都答应了邀请
客人们都已经来啦？
婚礼在四星期后才开始呢
- 别忘了，婚礼因为你住院推后了一个月
- 我知道
亲爱的，如果还是该延后的话...尽管...
不，不要那样
- 嗨
- 嗨，有进展吗？
不，还没有
我不知道丽茜能不能收到你的信
我也不知道，黛布拉在这
噢，那你再找时间打过来吧
好的，拜拜
是妈妈，问候下而已
- 她说了什么？
- 只是担心我
我也担心你啊
我很好，就有那么难相信吗？
对不起
行，我们有哪些嘉宾？
- 都排好了
- 好的
快点啊，丽茜。明早就是3号了
- 车夫！
- 女士？
你能载我去葛底斯堡吗？
葛底斯堡？那里正在打仗啊
求求你了！我今晚就得到那里
我把我能给你的都给你吧
这可不是钱的问题，女士
好吧，我找别人
车夫，能送我去葛底斯堡吗？
好吧，女士
- 我载你去吧
- 太感谢了！
同志们，上啊！
车夫，再快点行吗？
已经最快了！
丽茜...
- 车夫，你能在这里等我吗？
- 我会的
你好，士兵
你知道马塞诸塞州19号部队吗？
不再有了，小姐
叛军差点把它们全干掉了
那边有一些伤兵
凯勒
亲爱的
丽茜
凯勒
我答应过要娶你
没关系，我知道，我知道
- 说点东西
- 说什么？
你在河上念给我听的
- 陌生的你...？
- 是的
陌生的你，我们不该相会
但我又如此渴望和你在一起，梦着你
我会一直等待你，来轻轻地触摸我
尽管这个世界上没有...
但我们可以从现在开始...
你永远不会消失！
丽茜，亲爱的，你还好吧？
不好，妈妈
- 伊丽莎白，我有话...
- 爸，别！
亲爱的斯科特，我得到你的通知
但一切都太晚了
噢，亲爱的！
我失去了邓比上校，一起逝去的
多像是另一个你！
快写信给我
只有你是我的全部了
我...真的很抱歉
我知道你不想听到这些，但为你好...
妈妈，凯勒死了，丽茜的心都碎了
而我更没法寄信给她！
一个难以置信的奇迹发生在你身上
你也不会忘记的，但是都已结束了
是时候回到现实，想想你的未婚妻吧
你还是想和她结婚的，对吧？
嗨
你还好吧？
我们需要聊聊
聊什么？
读这些信吧
（献给凯勒）
丽茜小姐
我在桌下找到这封信
亲爱的丽茜：
不要停止写你的诗
你说过我们注定感受不到对方的触感
但你确确实实用你的诗句，触动了我
吟唱吧，我的挚爱！
我会一直聆听着你
我当然会的
这些是什么？
伊丽莎白・威仕肯写的信
她...
一直和我通信
她的信在隔间里消失了，然后...
我就收到了，并回给她
这...
真是荒唐透顶！
甚至是病态的！
这到底是什么？你...你在干嘛？！
- 我准备和你说...
- 说什么？
我爱上她了
伊丽莎白・威仕肯？！
我知道这很...
我不知道你到底有什么毛病
- 但这真的很吓人！
- 黛布拉，听我说
什么？
打开它吧
挚爱的，凯勒不在了，但我还有你，是吗？
我终于知道，原来你和他就是一个人
而在墓前
你给了我某些我已经失去的
尽管你听不到我的声音
但我仍给你低声唱这些诗歌
这简直是疯了！
这怎么可能？
我也不知道，但是千真万确！
- 这不可能！不可能！
- 听我说
但这真的就发生了
我也不清楚
很抱歉，我瞒着你，但这是真的
是真的
我对伊丽莎白的爱
对她的感受，都是真的
黛布拉
你需要一个更爱你的人
全心全意爱你的人
我还是尽量去理解这一切
但我也知道
如果你对我没什么感觉
那我们就不应该在一起
我不会忘记，时光是怎么捉弄我的
我也永远不会忘记，
我的心像圣诞树一样被点亮过...
无论我将会去往天堂，还是地狱
我最终都会被死神带走
但，我的挚爱，梦里的挚爱，我永世不忘...
她什么时候过身了？
周二
我很抱歉...我能进去吗？
- 你现在能做什么？
- 她把房子留给了我
所以我就住在这里了
介意我看看那房间最后一眼吗？
- 去吧
- 谢谢
丽茜？
你在这里吗？
丽茜...
斯科特...
我好想念你！
你还好吧，先生？
没...没事
克莱思把这些留给了你
她小时候在阁楼上找到的
一些信，日记，散文还有很多很多的诗
很有趣吧
克莱思发誓她小时候从来没看过这些诗
我猜她肯定是老了健忘了
（丽茜的诗）
亲爱的威仕肯小姐：
你是威洛比女校里我最爱的老师
太好了她后来当了老师
威仕肯小姐...
最后她还是没有嫁给那位里格“大人”
- 谁啊？
- 没事，无关紧要
丽茜...
那是你！
你...怎么会去到她的信里？！
我即是解释了
你也不会相信的
（伊丽莎白・威仕肯
卒于1901年8月7号，终年67岁）
（生于1834年3月23号）
我永世不忘...
喔，你什么来头啊？
快过来！
不要随便扑到陌生人身上
没关系的
- 很抱歉
- 没事
别介意
他肯定很喜欢你，不然也不会扑到你身上
怎么啦？
额，没...没有。狗狗很可爱
再次道歉了，实在没有冒犯你的意思
拜
乖
不好意思
你知道咖啡厅在哪里吗？
我知道，走3个街区有一个很好的咖啡厅
能带我去吗？
- 嗯，我请你喝杯吧
- 不用了
至少我乐意啊
- 好吧，你说的哦
- 行啦
- 我叫斯科特
- 叫我贝丝，很高兴认识你
（《伊丽莎白・威仕肯诗集》）
（斯科特・柯里根整理编辑）
- 全剧终 -
- Try for:
- Subtitle Length per line = 53 max
-2345678901234567890123456789012345678901234567890123
- The Love Letter (1998)
- aka Hallmark Hall of Fame: The Love Letter
- IMDB # 0140340
- Created by DonToribio (Subscence.Com  moniker)
- Honolulu, Hawaii
- March 2012
Perfect.
- Take a look?
- Yeah.
Ah, hello there, folks, I'm Jacob Campbell.
She's a beauty, isn't she?
- Can I try it on?
- No, I'm afraid it's not for sale.
Belonged to my grandmother.
Good way to get folks into the shop, though.
Especially pretty young ladies
draggin' in their fellas, hum?
Very clever.
- There're more gowns over here.
- Oh, great.
- Are you a Civil War buff?
- A bit, yes.
- Do you mind if I take a look back here?
- Oh, no, help yourself.
I'm a bit of a restorer myself.
Ah...
I got these in just the other day.
- Nice. - Very old.
- They're all right.
- Beautiful.
- That desk belonged to a Union general.
Really?
Deb, come take a look at this.
- Great, huh?
- It's kinda fallin' apart.
I need a desk.
- How much will you take for it?
- Well, I was plannin' on restoring it myself...
but, if you really want it...800?
- Too much, let's go.
- Will you take 600?
This is 19th century;
800's the best I can do.
I can't pay 800.
This is the first time I've ever
seen you do an impulse buy.
I thought you wanted me
to be more spontaneous.
Next time be spontaneous over
something a little less... heavy.
You know?  You're pretty
strong...for a girl.
It must be from throwing
all those manuscripts on the reject pile.
It must be.  Look at that! Huh?
Wait till ya see when I get a little
waxy-polish on this little polish...
I should go.
Get out.
All right.
Sweet dreams.
You, too.
Dearest, 'tis after midnight...
and I am at last free to speak to you.
Mother, father and Flossy
have grown accustomed
to my late night scribbling,
and have bid me goodnight.
In my 29 years I have been
called upon by several gentlemen.
But you are the one who occupies my thoughts.
Even though you are not real,
you are more dear to me...
than the man who has asked
just this night for my hand in marriage.
I do not love him.
To please father I have tried.
And...sadly, I know I have a duty to obey
and must soon accept.
But I ache for a love that burns like fire,
and moonlight.
I speak with you in my mind and heart.
If you only existed outside of them...
Goodnight, Sweetheart.
Dream of me.
Dear, Lady:
I have just read your letter
in the secret compartment of your desk,
and wish there were some way...
I know you feel an obligation to your father
but you have to obey your heart.
It's a mistake to marry someone you don't love.
Don't despair; the man of your dreams
may be out there in the mist right now,
just a heartbeat away.
Who knows? Perhaps I'm the one you seek.
But, unfortunately, My Dear,
I've already given my heart...
to Scarlett O'Hara.
Yours always, Rhett Butler.
I can see; when are you going to finish?
Stop worrying, Lester.
It's almost done.
I can see this game is gonna
kill us at Christmastime.
- What kind of attitude is that?
- It'll be ready.
It better be. Meanwhile
we'll kill 'em in the bike race.
- Or not.
- You're hovering. Stop hovering.
Information.
Boston.
Let's see now.
Yeah, oh yeah, here it is.
- Picked it up in Willoughby.
- Where's that?
Oh, a half an hour north
of here, up near Salem.
Address: Number 3, Mill Plain Road.
Big old place outside of town.
6:52! Signafact has a 6:50 flat.
I'm happy for them.
We're happy for them, aren't we?
- No way!
- I've had it!
Come on, we have less than six weeks
'til everlasting glory.
The coach says, "One more time!"
This is private property!
You trespassing!
I'm sorry, I don't mean
to intrude, I just...
Off of my property, now!
Actually, I'm just interested in
somebody who used to live here.
I know exactly what you interested in.
And we not interested.
Miss Clarice not goin' to no nursin' home.
And you can tell that to
the whole blasted cousin group.
But Ma'am...Ma’am.
Lesson number 2.
Please: Per favore.
Per favore.
Thank you.
- Grazie.
- Grazie
You've outdone yourself this time,
"mamma mia".
Before a trip one should
immerse oneself in the culture.
You have certainly done that.
And it's no more Beatriz,
I've got everyone calling me "Beatrice".
Beatri...May I stick with "Mom", please?
You know, with all the money
going into your wedding,
you and Deborah could take
a trip around the world.
- I don't want to take a trip around the world.
- See, that's your problem,
you get too stuck, Scotty.
Trapped in your own little universe.
Oh, really! Actually you are talking to a man who
just answered a 134 year old love letter.
Mi scusi?
Yeah, I found it in this antique desk I bought.
"I dream of you...
I speak only in my mind and heart...
if only you existed."
- You memorized it.
- There was something so...sad about it.
So, I just answered it.
And did you mail it?
Yes, I did, but you know
I don't trust the Post Office
so I sent it Pony Express.
Don't get smart!
H. G. Wells believed in time travel.
And Einstein thought that time
was just another dimension.
You know, some people believe
that souls can travel through time.
Can we travel through silence?
- Do you have an address?
- No! See! Naw, I knew it.
I shouldn't have told you.
You're gonna get carried away.
Opening my mail now.
Your mail?
Well, this is dated 1863...
it took a little time to get here
- Where did you get this?
- From the desk.
From a secret compartment.
You're kidding me!  Where?
Deb, I just walked in, I don't
feel like taking the desk apart.
Just asked.
Here.
In the drawer, there's a
little switch back here, and
That is so cool.
Poor thing.
Pouring her heart after nobody,
some fantasy guy.
Then she stuck it and married some
loser her father picked out for her.
Maybe she didn't marry him.
We're talking about the 1860's;
she married him.
I'm going to go check on dinner.
First class postage from Boston
to Willoughby in 1863 was one cent.
Careful with that, it wasn't cheap.
A bottle of ink. I got the Waterman people
to duplicate the formula they used back then.
Hold it! Hold it!
It's gotta be perfect or we don't have
a prayer of crossing the barrier.
Mother, stop!
Let's just say I bought into this madness
for a few milliseconds, which, of course, I don't
where would you suggest that I mail
this painstakingly authentic letter?
Manhasset Postal Substation on the north side...
built:1857, it's the only
pre-Civil War Post Office in existence.
It's open 24 hours for deposit.
Go at night. I'm not sure why
but it seems more appropriate.
Halt!
I really need to know something:
Do you think this is going to work?
Wouldn't it be awesome if it did?
Even though you are not real,
you are more dear to me
than the man who just this night
has asked for my hand in marriage.
I do not love him.
To please Father I have tried.
Sadly, I know I have the duty to obey
and must soon accept.
But I ache for a love that burns like fire
and moonlight.
I speak with you in
my mind and heart
If you only existed outside of them...
Goodnight, Sweetheart.
Dream of me.
Dear, Lady, I've just read the letter
from the secret compartment of your desk.
...which means, may be out there in
the mist right now, just a heartbeat away.
Who knows? Perhaps I'm the one you seek.
A friend.
Funny Farm, here I come!
- Good day to you, Mr. Potts.
- And to you, Maggie.
Elizabeth.
Elizabeth!
Flossy, have you seen your sister?
She's in the garden, Pap?.
- Miss Whitcomb?
- Mr. Reagle.
I found myself in the vicinity...
thought I'd take the liberty of stopping by.
How nice.
It's quite lovely, isn't it?
It's very lovely.
At midnight it should be in full bloom,
and then, come morning, it should be gone.
I'm trying to write a poem about her.
I do hope you read it to
me once it's completed.
I find your verses most...charming.
Thank you.
It looks like it'll be a lovely evening.
I have had some training.
I was wondering Miss Whitcomb...Lizzie.
Yes, Mr. Reagle?
I was wondering if you've had
an opportunity to consider the
the suggestion I made to you
during our previous visit.
Oh, yes, well, I'm still considering it.
Well...glad to hear that.
I...I fell one of my headaches coming on,
so I'm going to say goodnight.
Father, Mother, Floss
Oh...Lizzie...I forgot.
There's a letter for you.
Thank you, Mother.
Do feel better, Dear.
- Lizzie?
- Yes, Father?
Your mother and I wonder if
there's anything you wish to tell us.
No, Father.
I spoke at some length
earlier with Everett Reagle.
He's given me to believe that the
two of you have come to an understanding.
I have only agreed to what you might call
a prelude to an understanding.
I see.
And might this "prelude"...
lead eventually to an actual understanding?
An engagement?
And to a marriage?
Father, I don't love him.
You're 29 years old, Lizzie.
Father, I know you want
what you think is best for me.
And I know what is expected of me.
It's not merely our expectations,
it's common sense.
A woman of your years, however
comfortable her situation,
may scarcely afford to be reluctant
when a suitable match presents itself.
- Another headache?
- Yes, Father.
- Is there anything I can do?
- No, I just, I think I just need some sleep.
Who are you?
Sir!  I received your astonishing letter today,
and am amazed by your audacity.
Who are you?
And how could you know there was
something in my secret place to be stolen?
I wonder if I place the second letter
in the same place as the first,
am I in the tour for some feverish dream.
Or will you violate my privacy again?
In mystification,
Elizabeth Whitcomb.
Dear Elizabeth:
I'm sure you'll find this as
impossible to believe, as I do.
My name is Scott Corrigan.
I live in Boston,
but not the Boston you know.
While I write these words at my desk,
or rather, your desk, because I now
own the desk that sits in your bedroom,
I try to imagine how all
of this could have happened.
The only explanation I can come up with is,
that, for some reason,
the connection between us is so strong
that we're able to talk to each other
across the chasm of time.
If I haven't utterly terrified you,
please sit at OUR desk and write again soon.
Yours, Scott Corrigan.
Lizzie.
- Good heavens! What's the matter?
- Nothing!
You startled me.
I was somewhere else.
- Because of something in the letter?
- What letter?
The letter you're trying to hide from me.
Oh.
That letter.
No, no, no, it's just another
rejection from the publisher.
Oh, Lizzie, I'm sorry.
Your verses are...
transcendental.
If only Mr. Ralph W. Emerson,
of the New England Literary Journal,
felt the same way.
I still don't understand why...
you won't submit them to
Mr. Reagle for his magazine.
I have submitted them to Mr. Reagle.
I'm still awaiting a response.
I'm sure someone will print your verses.
You just have to be patient.
Dear, Mr. Corrigan:
I have decided to accept
that the laws of nature
as they apply to you and me
have been, for whatever reason,
temporarily suspended.
Okay! That was easy.
- How about flatware?
- Yes, yes, flatware.
You have the advantage over me
in that you know my most deepest secrets.,
while I know none of yours.
Tell me who you are and
how you live in your time
so many years in the future.
- How's this?
- It's too...Sci-Fi.
The most important of all,
tell me whether this conjunction between us
which I confess, I feel as strongly as you,
means that you, too, yearn
for a deep and passionate love.
How about this?
...or is there already someone you love.
Write soon, before the laws
of nature re-assert themselves.
Maybe we should just eat with our hands.
No, no, no. I’m sorry.
Dear, Lizzie, you have asked
some crucial questions.
- Have I?
- M’um?
Have I added the nutmeg?
Nutmeg, in pound cake?
What a peculiar recipe.
Cinnamon.  I meant have I added cinnamon.
Do I yearn for love?
Yes, of course.
Am I in love now.
I am engaged to be married, and...
yes, I believe I'm in love.
"I believe".
What, M'um?
I believe this is going to be a delicious cake.
Don't you, Maggie?
If you'll excuse me, M’um,
I'll see to the dusting room.
A friend once said that when you're in love,
you light up like a Christmas tree
when your lover enters the room.
I don't think I ever felt that way,
at least not until last night,
when I found your second letter.
- And how many does this make?
- Three, counting the first one.
And you're sure nobody is...?
playing some kind of bizarre joke? Impossible.
No!  This is impossible.
Mother, you're the one that talked
me into this insanity in the first place.
But I never dreamed...
- What in the world does Debra think about all this?
- I didn't tell her.
You didn't tell her?!?
- It's incredible, isn't it?
- I'll tell you what's incredible:
My son, who is engaged to
be married, is having an affair
with a woman who's been dead
for over a hundred years.
Mom, we write letters.
Letters that you keep secret from you fiancé.
And what about Elizabeth Whitcomb?
Scotty, you don't have the right to get
mixed up in a life that's already been lived.
If she doesn't love the guy,
she shouldn't marry him.
We should go.
Rome awaits you.
I can't believe we're
having this conversation.
- This woman doesn't exist!
- Then who wrote this?
In this world, in the world you
and I live in, she does not exist.
Then why do I feel...
the way I feel?
And what way is that?
My Dear Lizzie:
I can't begin to tell you
how wonderful I feel
as I read your letters.
I only wish I could hold you in my arms.
- Mr. Potts, could you look once more please?
- Yes, Miss Lizzie.
I'm sorry, there's...there's nothing.
Dearest: Another week gone
by and still no letter.
Are you worried that since you
told me of your engagement
I would think you a scoundrel
for professing tender feelings for me?
I'm worried about those
"tender feelings" in the first place.
I'm not so innocent as you
might think, Mr. Corrigan.
I have danced the waltz with many men.
And, I'm an avid reader
of the modern novel.
So, I  am au courant on
the subject of forbidden passion.
I'm afraid this waltz is going to have
to be mine and Debra's, Miss Whitcomb.
The hard truth is, we are
doomed to be chaste...
to never touch each other,
hear each other, see each other.
So, what harm can there be
to write to each other?
If you are still there,
write to me quickly and tell me
what it means to
"Light up like a Christmas Tree".
- Good Morning.
- You again.
I'm really sorry to bother you, I'm just
trying to find out about the Whitcombs.
Why?
Well, I bought a desk that
used to belong to one of them,
and I just became interested
in the family.
Thought I'd write a book about 'em.
A book!
They just regular folk.
You know who they were?
Clarice's grandma was a Whitcomb.
- Clarice?
- The lady I take care of.
You mean there's a Whitcomb
living in here right now?
That's right.  I've had 50 years
of her temper, and believe me,
it's worse than mine.
I'd really love to talk to her,
would that be possible?
She's sleeping.
I know this is an intrusion, but...
Would you mind if I
just took a peek inside?
Why would I let you do that?
I'll paint the house.
This side, anyway.
If you turn out to be one of them no-good
lawyers for Clarice's no-good cousins...
I'll take a rolling pin to you.
Yes, Ma'am.
- Okay, Mister, you've had your peek.
- Just a minute, please.
Mae, who is that you're
talkin' to down there?
Now you've done it!
Clarice.
Who are you?
This fellow's writin' a book...
about the Whitcombs.
He wanted to meet you.
How do you do, Ma'am,
my name is Scott.
- You're a fool, Mae, he's a lawyer.
- No Ma'am, I'm not a lawyer.
I told the whole lot of you,
I'm not leavin' this house,
until the good Lord takes me.
I'm just trying to find some
information about Elizabeth Whitcomb.
Liars, all of you!
Get out!
I warned ya.
How do you know about Lizzie?
I found a letter that she wrote,
in an old desk, probably from here.
Grandma Flossy told me
stories about my Aunt Elizabeth.
She was very beautiful.
I never knew her.
Can you tell me if she was ever married?
I need to sleep now.
I need to know if she was ever married.
Ma'am?
You coming?
Dear Lizzie: Ben Franklin named
it electricity
and we now use it
to power machines,
to light our homes,
and our Christmas trees.
Good morning, Miss Lizzie.
Thank you.
To light up like a Christmas tree
means to glow with pleasure,
and I am glowing...right now.
I went to your house on
Mill Plain Road...yes, it's still there.
A very old woman, your sister
Flossy's granddaughter lives in it.
And I actually stood in your bedroom.
But what I will never forget is
how I suddenly felt your presence
on the stairs. Almost as if
you touched my cheek.
It's crazy, but I felt as
if I could touch you, too.
Lizzie, to ignore what's happened
would be to deny a miracle.
Forgive my silence,
it won't happen again.
I promise, all my love, Scotty.
Darling Scotty, I beg you
please keep your promise.
Never stop writing again,
or I fear I shall stop breathing,
because my breath stop now
at the thought of you in
my house, in this very room.
Amazing as it seems,
I felt it, too,
in the very same place
on the stairs.
A touch like a sweet promise.
I know that we are tempting fate,
and in reality
there is your time,
and my time.
We shall live and love across time.
It's a deal.
I dream of you,
but I can't see your face.
Please, send me a picture.
Remember, you have to be still,
don't move.
I want you to look as if you
are about to walk into my arms.
- Hey! - How are you?
- I'm good. - Good
- How are you?
- Good, good, good.
You look so happy,
what happened?
...you're here!
Good answer.
Who's that?
That is Elizabeth Whitcomb.
- The one who wrote the letter?
- Yeah.
Well, where d'you get it?
Actually, I got it from someone
who lives in her old house.
- You went to her house?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- Just curious.
Well, how did d'you even find it?
I got some info from that antique guy. Stopped by
on the way back from practice. It's in Willoughby.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Well...
I guess I should be grateful that
the other woman's a dead one.
This parcel of land is for sale.
I know you love nature, Lizzie,
and that is uppermost in my mind
as I survey the region for a
for a possible future home...together.
I appreciate that.
- I was wondering, Mr. Reagle...
- Um-huh.
...if you'd had a chance to peruse
the verses I gave you a month ago.
Oh! Yes, yes.
I've read them, yes.
Well?
They're very interesting.
Very passionate.
Perhaps not quite as attentive as
they might be to the mechanics of the art.
The odd meters...broken rhymes.
You have aptitude;
you need guidance.
I hope in the future you will
allow me to provide it...
...in all things.
I have decided to cease writing poetry.
I know "His Reagle Highness"
is too conventional
to take me seriously.
until my work has been validated by others.
But the truth is, My Darling,
there are no others.
I sing, but nobody listens...except you.
So I offer you the last poem
I shall ever write.
- So, you and Deb doin' the marriage thing, huh?
- Yeah.
Yes, we're doin' the marriage thing.
- It's a great book.
- Thanks.
- Listen, Danny, can I ask you a favor?
Do you mind?
- Sure.
- Would you mind...sorry,
would you mind taking a look at a poem
and tell me what you think of it?
You want me to evaluate
your poem right here, right now?
It's not mine, it's a friends.
It's short. Do you mind?
- All right.
- Thank you.
"Stanger, not on this earth shall we meet
though surely I have lived a
life with you, I would wed etern..."
Tell him not to give up his day job.
What's a matter with it?
Besides being old fashioned,
sentimental and derivative?
You mean as opposed to the pretentious drivel
that gets published these days?
- What is your problem?
- I didn't have one until about 10 seconds ago.
- Oh, really, and what would that be?
- Ah...you!
- Really? - Yeah.
- Well, I seem to be...
What's going on?
I insulted his friend's poetry.
What's he talking about?
What friend?
Nothing. Nobody.
Well, it had to be somebody if you
almost came to blows over it.
It's Elizabeth Whitcomb's.
I found it in another drawer in the desk.
I just felt it might have
some historical significance.
Well, it has significance all right.
Debra.
- What's goin' on, Scotty?
- Nothing. Nothing's going on.
First you don't tell me about finding her letter.
And then you go tracking down
Elizabeth Whitcomb's house,
and you don't tell me about
that either, and then you
don't tell me about getting
her picture or about finding her poem.
- Honey, you're blowing this out of proportion.
- No! Don't! You're putting
more energy into Elizabeth Whitcomb
than you are into our wedding plans.
- It's not true!
- I want to know why, I mean
- are you that freaked-out about getting married?
Is that what this is?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
Because if you don't want to do this,
Scotty, you just say the word.
Be honest and tell me, because we'll call it off.
I do...I don't want to call it off,  okay?
I'm sorry, okay?
It's my fault, it means nothing, okay?
Dear Lizzie, please don't
stop writing your poetry.
First of all, this Reagle guy sounds like he wouldn't
know a good poem if it smacked him in the face.
You say you sing but nobody listens?
Maybe that's true for now, but what about
in 10 years?  In 100 years?
You once said we were doomed
never to touch each other,
but you did touch me...with your words.
Keep singing, My Love.
I'll always be here to listen.
Oh, Floss, there's nothing to worry about.
Then why do you have to go all the way to Boston?
The doctor thinks my headaches may have
something to do with my eyes.
And there's a specialist there.
I'm coming with you.  Cousin Delia
has plenty of room.
No, Floss.
I need you here.
I'm going to tell you something
that may sound rather strange.
Even a little mad,
but I assure you it's true.
Now, I need you to promise me not to
interrupt until I'm finished.
Riders, ready!
5... 4... 3... 2... 1... GO!!
So, I take the letters that you send
to me here from Mr.  Corrigan...
put them in that compartment, close it, and they...
And you must promise to send his letter
to me care of Cousin Delia in Boston.
Is he going to be okay?
The EEG does indicate some brain swelling
but fortunately his vital signs are stable.
When will he come out of it?
Right now it's just impossible to know.
Elizabeth Whitcomb to see Dr. Reed.
- Please take a seat, Miss Whitcomb.
- Thank you.
We'll have an accommodation room
for you shortly, Miss Whitcomb.
Colonel Denby.
- 'til Friday, Colonel.
- Yes, thank you..
Miss Whitcomb, follow me.
I'm so sorry.
- Miss Whitcomb, I...
- Colonel Denby.
- What a coincidence.
- Pardon my clumsiness.
Oh, it's all right, you seemed in a hurry.
Yes.
Well, don't let me keep you.
Might I accompany you, Miss Whitcomb?
Well, I...I wouldn't want to
interfere with your plans.
No, you're not, I have none.
I mean, ah....
Where is your destination?
Actually, I'm not quite sure.
Perhaps you'd allow me to buy you a cup of tea
and we can decide where we're going.
All right.
Have you long been a patient of Dr. Reed's?
No, this was my first visit.
Are you present...forgive me, feeling poorly?
No, at present I fell quite well.
Forgive my boldness, may I
ask you a strange question?
Yes.
How is it I have the total
conviction that I know you?
I don't know, but I feel the same.
My Dearest Scotty: This afternoon I met
a gentleman named Caleb Denby.
Presently a colonel commanding
the 19th Massachusetts.
Scotty, the moment I saw him,
I was powerfully drawn to him.
And he, it appears, seems to feel
an attraction as well.
Please do not fear, My Darling, that I am
in any way moving away from you.
For I feel, strange as it may seem,
that being with Caleb, brings me closer to you.
I have the uncanny feeling that
what is happening, it is meant to happen.
You promised to read to me.
- Oh, no, please!
- Please.
All right, let me see.
No laughing!
"Stranger, not on this earth shall we meet.
But surely, I have lived a life
and have dreamed of you.
I would wait eternity to touch you.
It's okay, it's okay.
Dearest Scotty, I despair at ever
hearing from you again.
Flossy assures me that my letters to you continue
to miraculously vanish from the secret compartment.
So I pray that you are still connected to me,
reading this by one of your
"electrical lights", and understand it.
Gracious ladies and fine gentlemen,
thank you for coming.
Allow me to introduce the guest speaker
who will tell you what your attendance
and your generous contributions mean
to the wounded soldiers of our Great State.
This brave officer was grievously injured
at Chancellorsville, but he is returning
to his regiment this very week.
Let's all give a warm welcome
to Colonel Caleb Denby
of the 19th Massachusetts Infantry.
You didn't tell me you were coming here tonight.
- I thought I'd surprise you.
- Well, you have.
- You're not seriously going back, are you?
- I have to.
- How long do we have?
- I leave day after tomorrow.
Lizzie, I need to see you alone.
Will you meet me tonight on The Common?
- I can't...my Cousin Delia.
- What?
...practically asleep now.
Lizzie.
- I kind of organized it for you.  - Great. Thanks.
- Um-huh.  - Sure.
So, um, maybe you should go up and lie down.
No, I'm fine.  I'm fine, I'm fine.
Look! See! I'm fine.
I'm nimble.
...well...
- Are you all right?
- I'm all right. I'm okay.
- I'm cancelling my meeting.
- I'm fine, Debra, I'm fine.
Just a little dizzy, the Doctor said
that was normal...normal dizziness, okay?
All right? My mother's coming over,
she'll cook Italian...
I have to get back to living
sooner or later, right?
Right.
- Promise you'll call me.
- I promise.
Great.
Scott...
When you...when you woke up in the Hospital...
Yeah?
Nothing. Just glad you're back.
Me, too.
...I am powerfully drawn to him
and he, it appears
seems to feel an attraction as well.
Very soon, he will be returning to his regiment.
He says there are rumors of a decisive battle
somewhere in southern Pennsylvania.
Darling, I am so frightened.
Southern Pennsylvania.
Southern Pennsylvania in 1863.
Southern Pennsylvania. Gettysburg!
Gettysburg, Gettysburg.
19th, 19th Massachu...
19th Mass.
50 per cent.
...Delaney, Denby!
Colonel Caleb Denby, killed in action July 3rd.
June 28th.
Dearest Lizzie:
Do not let Colonel Denby return to his regiment.
- Where are you going.
- Post Office.
- You just got out of the Hospital!
- I have to get this to Lizzie.
- Scotty, you cannot drive there!
- Yes, I can!
- All right, I'll drive!
- What's that?
- That's the Post Office.
- ...back behind the barricade there, Sir.
- Sir, I'm sorry. I need to get in there.
- I know. Please, please behind the barricade!
You can't go in there.
- Stay here. I'm just gonna go in for a second.
- No! - Stay! Wait here!
No! No! Scotty! No! Come back!
When I come back, will you marry me?
Yes.
- Are you sure, Flossy?
- I check each day.
And my letter to him?
They vanished, just as you said.
He promised.
Lizzie, Dear.
Mr. Reagle has just arrived to welcome you home.
Oh, no, Mother. I...I...I can't just now.
Your father's told him you'd be right down.
Just freshen up a bit, Dear.
I'm sure seeing him will lift your spirits.
Well, I do believe with General Grant
permanently in charge now
the Western Campaign will be going much...
I anticipate a speedy and comprehensive victory.
Oh, I...I hope you're all right, Sir.
Welcome back, Miss Whitcomb.
You were missed by all.
Thank you, Mr. Reagle.
I hope you will forgive me, but I'm
rather fatigued, it was a long journey.
And I'd like to postpone this visit.
Lizzie...I've asked Mr. Reagle to join us at dinner.
Maggie.
- Is there something for me?
- Yes, M'um. only this.
Lizzie, can you not be
more considerate of our guest?
In a moment, Father.
Lizzie, what is it?
Get my bag, Flossy! Hurry!
Father, I have to go to the Station right away.
But you've just this minute come
from the Station. What was in that letter?
Mr. Reagle, will you give me a
ride in your shay, please?
Dear Lady, I..I would do
anything to please you, but...
against the wishes of your father...
Then I shall walk.
- I forbid it!
- I am not a child, Father.
You can't stop me.
This is what comes of letting
her go to Boston unattended.
Warren!
Flossy, what did she tell you?
Lizzie!
Excuse me.
Does this train go anywhere near Gettysburg?
Naw. Closest you can get, Ma'am, is Harrisburg,
if the Rebs ain't cut the line yet.
- You'll have to take a carriage from there.
- Thank you.
All aboard!
- Oh, hi. -Hi.
- You're here.
Yeah.
Look what I got.
Lots of yeses.
People wrote back already, huh?
The wedding's four weeks away.
- Don't forget, you lost a month.
- I know, I know, sorry.
Honey...
If you think that we should postpone this,
maybe it would be difficult but we could do it.
- No, I don't want to do that, Honey.
- Fine.
- Hello.
Any word?
Uh...no, not yet.
I wonder if she even got the letter.
Yeah, I was wondering that, too.
Listen, Debra's here.
Sorry.  Well, send her my love and call
me if you hear anything, okay?
Okay, bye-bye.
That was mom, she send her love.
- What ..what was that all about?
- Uh...she's just worried about me.
That makes two of us.
I'm fine.  Why is that so difficult to believe?
I'm sorry.
Okay.  Whatta we got here?
- I'm just trying to do this second stack.
- All right.
C'mon, Lizzie, it starts at dawn.
Conductor.
Ma’am?
Will you take me to Gettysburg?
Gettysburg! The heaviest fightin'
in the war is goin' on up there!
Please, please take me.
I have to get there tonight.
I'll...I'll pay you anything that you like.
It ain't the money, Ma’am
Fine! I'll find someone else.
Driver. Will you please take me to Gettysburg?
All right, Ma’am.
- I'll take you to Gettysburg.
- Thank you, Sir.
Forward, Boys!
Driver, can't you go any faster?
The horses are goin' as fast as they can, Ma’am.
- Driver, will you wait for me, please?
- Yes, Ma’am.
Soldier!
Do you know where the 19th Massachusetts is?
There ain't no more 19th Massachusetts, Ma’am.
The Rebs got 'em, got 'em good.
What's left is over there.
Caleb.
Darling.
Lizzie.
Caleb.
I promised to marry you.
It's okay, it's all right. It's all right.
- Say something.
- What?
Like on the river, say something.
"Stranger, not on this Earth... "
"Stranger, not on this Earth shall we meet...
though I have surely lived with you,
dreamed of you,
I would wait eternity to touch you.
Not in this world Outsized...
Falling forward,
Never to lose you".
Lizzie, Dear, are you all right?
No, Mother, I am not.
- Elizabeth...
- Not now, Father.
Dearest, Scotty: I received your warning,
but it was too late.
Oh, my Darling.
My Colonel is gone, and with him
went that part of you
I never thought to hold.
So, write to me.
For you're all of him that remains.
I'm so sorry.
I know you don't want to hear this,
but it's for the best.
Mother, Caleb is dead, Lizzie's heart
is broken and I can't even reach her.
An incredible miracle happened, Scotty.
And you'll never forget it, but it's over.
It's time for you to be in the present
with the woman you're about to marry.
You do still want to marry her, don't you?
Hi.
Are you all right?
We need to talk.
What is it?
Read these.
Miss Lizzie.
I found this letter after you left.
Dear Lizzie: Please do not stop
writing your poetry.
You once said we were doomed
to never touch each other,
but you did touch me...with your words.
Keep singing, My Love.
I'll always be here to listen.
No.
Of course.
What are these?
Elizabeth Whitcomb wrote them.
She's...
been writing to me.
Her letters just appear in the desk,
and then...
I write back to her.
What you're telling me...
What you're telling me is...crazy.
It's insane.
What, what, what, what is this?
What are you doing?
- I'm trying to show you, I'm trying to tell you.
- Tell me what?
I fell in love with her.
Elizabeth Whitcomb?
I know it sounds...
I don't know what that accident did to you,
- but this is really frightening, and...
- Deb, listen to me.
What?
Open it.
Dearest, Caleb is dead, and so,
My Future Love, are you.
It must be so, for you are one in the same.
I know that now.
But almost, as if from the grave
you have returned to me
something I thought I had lost:
My voice, although you may never hear it,
I am enclosing this song for you.
This is crazy.
How can this be?
I don't know, but it's true.
This isn't happening, this is not possible.
It is happening, it is happening.
I don't understand it.
I'm sorry I dragged you through it, but it's real.
But it is real.
The love I felt for this woman,
that I feel for her...is real.
Debra.
You deserve to be loved...
completely.
I'm not even going to try
to understand what's happening.
But I know this...
if you don't feel that way about me,
we shouldn't be together.
I will never forget how the winds
of time blew back and forth for me.
I will never forget how my heart lit up
like a glowing Christmas tree.
Though I wander in the hell or heaven,
my slate wiped clean by death,
of you, My Love, My Dream Love,
I'll never, ever forget.
When?
Tuesday.
I'm sorry. May I come in?
- So, what will you do now?
- Well, she left me the house, so,
I'll stay a while and see how it feels.
Would you mind if I took one last look at her room?
- Suit yourself.
- Thanks.
Lizzie.
Are you here?
Oh, Scott.
I miss you so much.
Are you all right, Mister?
Yes, Ma’am
Clarice wanted you to have this.
She found it in the attic
when she was a little girl.
It's a batch of letters, diaries, papers,
and poems, lots of poems.
It's funny,
Clarice could swear there were
no poems in it when she was a kid.
Of course she was getting
pretty forgetful there at the end.
"Dear Miss Whitcomb: You're my favorite
teacher at Willoughby School for Girls.
She became a teacher. That's great.
Miss Whitcomb, Miss Whitcomb.
Guess she didn't marry
His Reagle Highness, after all.
- Who?
- Nothing, it's not important.
Lizzie.
That's you!
How did you get in there?
I'll try to explain, but...
You're never gonna believe it.
"I never forgot".
Whoa, whoa, who are you? Hey! Stay!
Orbit, come! Come here, Boy!
Come here Boy, quick, quick!
And no jumping on strangers!
It's all right.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
Don't worry about it.
He must really like you.
He doesn't usually jump on people.
Is something wrong?
No, no, nothing. Sorry.
Sorry, he's all right.
Well, again, sorry.
I didn't mean to intrude.
Bye.
Good Boy!
Excuse me, sorry.
Do you know where I could get
a good cup of coffee, or...
Yeah! I know a know a really good place,
actually, it's like three blocks from here.
Could you show me?
- Can I buy you a cup...
- No, no. That's all right.
No, really, it's the least we can do.
- You talked me into it.
- Okay, then.
- I'm Scott.
- Hi. Beth.
Poems by Elizabeth Whitcomb, edited by Scott Corrigan.